# **Devang Tomar**

E-mail: devangtomar123@gmail.com § Phone: +91-9634176099

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/devang-tomar-8814aa138/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/devang-tomar-8814aa138/</a>

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/Devang-Tomar">https://github.com/Devang-Tomar</a>

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Creative and Passionate Senior Software Engineer offering 3 years of experience with customer facing environment. Have expertise in several domains including Cloud Computing, Infrastructure Automation, Python and shell scripting, CI/CD tool, Networking, Containerization, Linux Administration. Broad Understanding of Infrastructure automation along with version control. Resourceful and adaptable approach to challenges. Proud team player focused on achieving project objectives with speed and accuracy.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Wipro Limited at Cisco Systems Inc, Bangalore

May 2018 — Present

Senior Software Engineer

- Writing infrastructure code in IaC (infrastructure as code) software tool (Ansible) to safely and predictably create, change, and improve infrastructure (Azure, containers and VMs)
- Syslog molding and server management using Python and bash scripts plus, automating task over the Linux server.
- Fetching data from multiple data sources using SQL queries and then modelling that unstructured data into structured data and furthermore feeding that data into different KPI metrics and delivering over email.
- DevOps operations and data pipelining into Grafana and ELK stack hosted over cloud (Azure).
- Deployment of Cisco UCS Servers, Installing VMware ESXi Hosts and NAT (PFsense and CSR1000V) deployment and configuration within VMs.
- Web-scrapping from different portals using python, selenium browser automation and feeding this data into NodeJS based chat-bot.
- Monitor/Troubleshoot Inventory & configuration collection from Cisco switches/routers and SNMPv2/v3, Telnet & SSH are used for data collection.
- Patching automation for 500 servers of APJC & ANZ region. Patching time reduced 30% man-hour than before.
- Syslog Management in network devices using NFS, custom script & direct transfer via port 514 Create, configure & manage virtual machines for various cisco services over cloud and various hypervisors.

#### Center Of Development of Telematics, New Delhi

Apr 2017 — Nov 2017

Software Intern

- Developed processes to automate tasks, resulting in 20% increase in efficiency.
- Supported software engineering projects in Agile work environment.
- Produced clean, validation-ready code for project needs.

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Microsoft Certified: Azure Administrator

Link: Credly Badge

• Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

Link: Credly Badge

# **EDUCATION**

2014 - 2018 Bachelors: Technology - Computer Science

DIT University, GPA: 7.8/10

High School

Kendriya Vidyalaya ONGC - Dehradun, GPA: 8.5/10

2012 Secondary School

Seven Oaks School - Dehradun, GPA: 9.2/10

# **PROJECTS**

- "Optical Character Reader (OCR) Android App with TTS (Text-To-Speech Engine)"
  The Android app will be manipulating an image and getting the matter/gist out of the image, which can further be translated into user-preferable language and an additional utility will be the TTS Engine (Text-To-Speech).
  The TTS engine will be in use if the user is visually impaired or wants the text in image to be read out in the same or language preferred by him/her.
- "UI Component Development using Canvas and Angular JS"

  Designed and implemented Chassis-view for the device and its configured components, such as interfaces, nodes, line-cards, hardware-components, sub racks, cable trays. The Chassis-view indicates the state of the Network interfaces.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Continuous Monitoring: *Grafana*, *ELK*
- Cloud: Azure
- OS: Linux administrator (CentOS, Ubuntu), Windows (all versions).
- Databases: MySQL and Elasticsearch
- Language: Python
- Python Modules: Regex, Selenium, Request, Tkinter, Beautiful Soup, REST, Tensor Flow, NumPy, Pandas, Plotly.
- Configuration management and deployment: Ansible and Azure ARM
- Container and orchestration: Docker, Kubernetes.
- Version Control: *Git and GitHub*
- CI/CD: Jenkins